



## CONTACT

Mobile	(972) 567-5105
Email	mac_hopper@mac.com

#### LINKS



www.macauleyhopper.com



www.linkedin.com/in/machopper

### Personal Statement

I love game design, helping create unique and engaging systems for players is a truly rewarding experience. Being able to work with artists, programmers, and more to bring a game to life is amazing to say the least. Video games are a huge aspect of my life, I love crafting unique and engaging experiences for players that they will continue to talk about for years to come.

# Professional Experience

#### 2018

### Digital Producer - Contract

Cactex Media, Dallas, TX - October 2018 - December 2018

- $\bullet$  Created detailed timelines, wire frames, menu mockups, and wire layouts
- Kept track of multiple applications requirements
- Worked with stakeholders and creative leads to ensure projects met their company needs
- · Worked with a team and stakeholders to stay on schedule and solve any and all roadblocks
- Developed storyboards for video and demos

## Configuration Management Engineer

XO Communications, Plano, TX - October 2014 - March 2018

- $\bullet \ \mathsf{Created} \ \mathsf{documentation} \ \mathsf{for} \ \mathsf{various} \ \mathsf{applications}, \mathsf{including} \ \mathsf{Git}, \mathsf{SourceTree}, \mathsf{Tortoise} \ \mathsf{Git}, \mathsf{and} \ \mathsf{Team} \ \mathsf{Foundation} \ \mathsf{Server}.$
- Managed Agile development process, hosting daily scrums with 10 developers.
- Provided support for Git development tool and build environments.

## Personal Projects

#### Current

## Designer & Producer - A.R.C.H.O.N

Tiny Tyrants, Plano, TX - January 2015 - Present

 $\bullet \ \, \text{Designed and documented the destructible environment mechanic, event card system, and all armor and weapons.}$ 

 $\bullet \ Collaborated \ with \ artists \ to \ ensure \ the \ armor \ pieces \ and \ we apons \ were \ able \ to \ work \ with \ the \ players' \ ARCHON \ cards.$ 

- Studied and maintained target demographic studies for optimal customer reach.
- $\bullet \, \mathsf{Led} \, \mathsf{play} \, \mathsf{testing} \, \mathsf{sessions}, \mathsf{and} \, \mathsf{designed} \, \mathsf{and} \, \mathsf{balanced} \, \mathsf{the} \, \mathsf{armor} \, \mathsf{and} \, \mathsf{weapon} \, \mathsf{systems}.$
- 2014

## Designer & Producer - Five Suns

Studio Hue, Savannah, GA - January 2014 - June 2014

- Designed and documented the moment-to-moment gameplay, including the combat system, enemy classes, and spell sets.
- $\bullet \, \mathsf{Led} \, \mathsf{play} \, \mathsf{testing} \, \mathsf{and} \, \mathsf{daily} \, \mathsf{scrum} \, \mathsf{sessions}, \mathsf{and} \, \mathsf{oversaw} \, \mathsf{cast} \, \mathsf{and} \, \mathsf{crew} \, \mathsf{production} \, \mathsf{schedule}.$
- Presented results of the play testing sessions to various departmental personnel.
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Directly responsible for all project deadlines, including all art assets, design principals, voice work, \ and \ casting.}$
- Received Entelechy 2014 Best 2D Game Award.

#### 2013

#### Designer & Producer - Vallo

Savannah College of Art and Design, Savannah, GA - September 2013 - November 2013

- Designed and documented a RTS RPG Tower Defense game
- $\bullet \ Worked \ with \ 2 \ free lance \ artists \ to \ help \ create \ concept \ art \ for \ the \ project$
- Designer & Producer Flight of the Meridian

Savannah College of Art and Design, Savannah, GA - September 2013 - November 2013

- Designed and documented a 3 versus 1 board game
- $\bullet \mbox{Worked with 2 freelance artists to help create concept art for the project } \\$

## EDUCATION



Savannah, College of Art and Design, Savannah GA Bachelor of Fine Arts in Interactive Design and Game Development 2014

## SOFTWARE

Autodesk Maya
Unreal Development Kit
Adobe Creative Suite
Google Product Suite
Jira
Team Foundation Server
Git
Microsoft Office